Roller Coaster Rabbit is a family, comedy,
animation film directed by Rob Minkoff.
Roger Rabbit struggles to keep wandering Baby Herman safe in an
amusement park where the usual havoc ensues.
Roger Rabbit (voice), played by Charles Fleischer.
Jessica Rabbit (voice), played by Kathleen Turner.
Young Baby Herman / Mrs. Herman (voice), played by April Winchell.
Adult Baby Herman (voice), played by Lou Hirsch.
Droopy Dog (voice), played by Corey Burton.
Bull (voice), played by Frank Welker.
The Roger Rabbit shorts are a series of three live-action/animated short films
produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation from 1989 to 1993.
They feature Roger Rabbit, the animated protagonist from Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988), being enlisted to care for
Baby Herman while his mother is absent, resulting in a plot defined by slapstick humor and visual gags.
Each short concludes with a sequence involving live-action and animation, in which the
characters interact with live-action human beings, akin to the 1988 film.
Droopy Dog from MGM makes a cameo in all of the shorts.
Charles Fleischer, Kathleen Turner, Lou Hirsch, and April Winchell returned to reprise their voice roles from
the film, alongside producers Steven Spielberg, Kathleen Kennedy, Frank Marshall, and Don Hahn.
Marshall also directed the live-action segments in the first two shorts, while Industrial
Light & Magic (ILM) was responsible for the live-action visual effects.
Produced in association with Spielberg's Amblin Entertainment, the three shorts (Tummy Trouble, Roller Coaster Rabbit
and Trail Mix-Up) were originally attached to the theatrical releases of several Disney and Amblin films.
A fourth short, Hare in My Soup, was cancelled during pre-production, with three more (Clean and
Oppressed, Beach Blanket Bay and Bronco Bustin' Bunny) in the planning stages also cancelled.
Despite being produced by Walt Disney Animation, these shorts heavily
contained a similar slapstick style to Warner Bros.
Looney Tunes or Tex Avery cartoons, and MGM
character Droopy made cameos in every one.
The film explores themes of cartoon, roller coaster
/ rollercoaster, cartoon rabbit.
The tone is lighthearted.